[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
So the normalized count vectors that we just described helped address some
上节我们提到的归一化向量
of the issues with our original proposal of just using raw
解决了我们最初提出的使用单词统计来表示文档
word counts as our representation of the document.
产生的一些问题
But there's another issue, which is often what we'd like to do is really
但是还有一个问题是 我们通常希望强调
emphasize the important words in a document.
文档里的关键词
So we're gonna discuss a little bit about what it means to be an important word and
下面我们简单讨论一下什么是关键词
how we can think about emphasizing them.
以及我们可以如何考虑强调它们
Okay, before we talk about important words, let's first talk about rare words.
在讨论关键词之前 我们先说说生僻词
So again, let's imagine that we're reading an article about soccer, and
再次设想一下 我们正在读一篇关于足球的文章
in this article there are lots and lots of common words like the and
这篇文章里有很多常用词例如 the and
player and field and goal.
球员(player)  场地(field) 和  进球(goal)
And what we mean by a common word,
我们所说的常用词
it's a word that appears frequently in the corpus.
是指语料库中出现频率高的词
In the corpus, that's just terminology for all the documents out there
语料库只是一个术语 用来代指我们在执行检索时
that we are looking at when we're doing this task of retrieval.
查看的所有文档的总和
And what happens though is that these common words dominate the similarity
现在的情况是 这些常用词决定了
metric that we talked about when we compare against other documents because,
我们前面所说的文档间相似度的度量
like I said, these words appear in lots and lots of documents.
这是因为 就像我说的 这些词出现在很多很多文档中
Whereas in contrast,
与之相对的是
there are some very rare words in this document we're looking at.
我们考虑的文档中可能有一些非常生僻的词
Words like "futbol" and "Messi", the specific player we're reading about,
比如单词futbol或是 我们正在读的球员的名字 梅西(Messi)
that get completely swamped by all these common words.
这些单词完全被常用词淹没了
And these words, like "futbol" and "Messi",
像futbol或是Messi之类的单词 它们被
they get swamped because they just appear very infrequently in the corpus.
淹没的原因是它们在语料库中极少见
So let's think about how to increase the importance of these rare words,
所以让我们想想如何增加这些生僻词的重要性
because those often are the ones that are really relevant in describing what's
因为通常这些词才真正描述了这篇文章的独特之处
unique about this article, and what might indicate which other articles out there,
以及指示其他 比如Carlos
Carlos for example, is interested in reading.
感兴趣阅读的文章
Okay, so like we said, what characterizes a rare word is the fact
好了 就像我说过的 生僻词的特征是
that it infrequently appears in the corpus and
其在语料库中很少见
what we wanna do is we somehow wanna up-weight these rare words and
我们要做的是设法增加这些词的权重
equivalently to thinking about emphasizing words that only appear in a few documents,
及等价地为了强调那些仅在部分文档中出现的词
we can think about taking each word and discounting the weight on that
对每个单词 我们根据其出现在语料库中的文档数
word based on how many documents that word appears in in the entire corpus.
减少其权重
Okay, so a question is, do we really want to just emphasize the rare words?
现在的问题是 我们只想要强调生僻词吗?
Well, we clearly don't want to emphasize the very common words,
我们无疑不想强调常用词
the words like the and a and it and everything like that.
像 the a it 所有此类的单词
But what we wanna include are things that are very relevant for that document.
但是我们想要包含的是与文章内容相关的词
So not just words like Messi, but also probably soccer and field and goal.
不仅包括单词Messi 还有可能是单词足球 soccer 场地 field及 进球goal
Things that describe the sport that we're looking at,
所有这些描述我们在看的关于这项运动的文章的单词
which might be different than even another article about sports.
甚至可以跟描述其他运动的文章中的词区别开
An article about basketball that talks about basketball
一篇关于篮球的文章可能有basketball
hoop and court and words like that.
篮筐(hoop) 前场 后场(court)等单词
So in this case, we wanna emphasize what I'll call important words.
在这种情况下 我们想要强调那些我称之为关键词的单词
Okay?
明白?
And so what we're gonna trade off here is we're gonna think about
所以我们需要权衡的是考虑那些
Words that appear very frequently in the document so
在文挡中出现频率非常高
they're relevant to the document that we're currently reading.
所以跟我们在读的文档相关的单词
So I'll call this common locally.
我称之为局部常见
And at the same time we want them to appear relatively infrequently in
同时我们希望这些词在语料库中相对少见
the corpus so I'll call this rare globally and what characterizes a quote unquote
所以我称之为全局罕见 描述所谓关键词的特征
important word Is some trade off between this local frequency, and global rarity.
就是某种局部出现率和全局罕有率的权衡
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community